Hello, everyone, and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco, and I'm joined here with Jen.
Hello.
And Jason.
Hey, everybody.
So, you may not know Jason or Jen, but they actually do work here.
It's true.
We didn't just pop in off the street.
You may have heard Jason and Jen actually in some of our recent dialogues.
They've been doing some voice acting.
Oh, yeah.
And from that, Jason is the official translator from Chinese to English for ChinesePod.
That's right.
So, we also have Praxis Languages also offers ChinesePod, which is another website for people
studying Chinese, and that's the part of the company that I work at.
Right.
Shameless plug.
ChinesePod.
All right.
And Jen also hosts the Chinese version of EnglishPod with the other Jason, Jason Chen.
Yeah.
It's not confusing at all.
No, not at all.
Jen, Jason, Jason Chen.
There's a lot of J's in the office.
Yeah.
A lot of J's.
And then there's...
Okay.
There's Jenny Joo, the ubiquitous Jenny Joo from ChinesePod.
SpanishPod has a Jenny.
Jenny.
Yeah.
From Cuba.
I thought there was no J in Spanish.
What's going on here?
It's spelled with a Y.
And there is a J in Spanish.
What are you talking about?
I don't know, man.
Yeah, but it's not a J sound.
I work at ChinesePod.
Okay.
Yeah.
So, I'm Jen.
All right.
So, we have...
They're going to be joining us today.
We're going to talk about upcoming lessons.
Jason is an interesting guy.
Am I really now?
Anybody with that little hair should be interesting.
Yeah.
And you also know a lot of Chinese that says a lot about you.
I do know quite a bit of Chinese, apparently so.
Which is why you were hired as a translator.
Translating.
I think that might have been it.
So, what's going on at EnglishPod Global this week, Marco?
Phyllis and...
On Monday, we have a lesson called Adventure Sports.
So, we're going to talk about extreme sports.
That's cool.
I used to skateboard, actually, in high school.
Really?
Is that an adventure sport?
I don't know.
I went on quite a few adventures with my skateboard, but I don't know if it was...
How many people have died skateboarding?
That?
I don't know, actually.
But I think a lot of people...
I have gone skydiving, actually.
Next.
Oh, really?
And it was exhilarating.
I bet.
I would love to do it again.
I would be way too afraid to ever go skydiving.
I would pee my pants.
I was very scared, believe me, but I didn't, because, you know, the guy was telling me,
I said, I don't know if I can do this.
I'm totally afraid of heights.
He said...
Oh, you're afraid of heights, and you went skydiving.
Yeah.
How did that work?
It happened.
He just said, you know, you get up, and you just have to jump out.
And that's all you got to do.
And he's like, just jump, you know.
And he's like, that's the one thing you have to do, and you're done.
That's awesome.
That's such a simple view.
You got one job to do.
Jump.
Did you have your doubts before jumping out of the airplane?
I was thinking, I'm going to die, I'm going to die, I'm going to die.
But I didn't die, so...
But you put yourself voluntarily into this.
Yeah.
Why did you get into the airplane?
It was my brother's bachelor party.
We went skydiving.
There you go.
Oh, you went skydiving for your brother's bachelor.
It's one of those remarkably stupid things at bachelor parties, I understand.
I'm a girl, so, you know, I don't know.
Well, we're going to talk about skydiving, hang gliding, river rafting, whitewater rafting,
all that good stuff.
Even apparently hot air ballooning is an adventure sport.
Yeah, I wouldn't call it an extreme sport.
No, it's not an extreme sport, but it's an adventure sport.
You go really high in your hair.
That's pretty extreme.
Well, you go really high in the air in an airplane, and that's not, you know, anything
adventure sports.
But you're basically being held up by a huge balloon, and you have no control as to where
it goes.
Interesting.
I think you do have a little bit of control.
No, you don't.
You don't.
Yeah, you do.
No, you can just control how high or if you want to come down, but you can't make a turn.
How did the guy who went around the world in the hot air balloon do it in the...
Wind currents.
So he can control the wind currents.
No, he can't control the wind currents.
He can't control the wind currents.
Then he subjects his balloon to.
But you can, like, sort of direct yourself by wind currents.
No, no.
You just...
You put...
You're subject...
Which wind current you're going to catch.
Yeah, but you can't.
Like, you can't say, oh, I'm going to turn left here.
It's like, no, no.
Well, what if you attached rocket boosters to the basket?
Then you would have...
This is wild, wild west.
Have you ever seen the Cantimplas movie?
No.
With the...
I don't know if you guys in...
If our listeners out there are familiar with Cantimplas, he's a Mexican comedian, really
funny guy.
And he made a movie...
Like around the world in 80 days.
Yeah, around the world in 80 days.
And there was...
There's a Jackie Chan version of that as well.
Jackie Chan version of that movie.
Yeah.
There's a...
Oh, over the world.
Cantimplas kicks Jackie Chan's proverbial ass.
All right.
So on Wednesday, we are getting a pet.
We are here at the office.
No.
No, I got excited.
I was excited.
Well, you have a pet.
You have a cat.
I do.
I have a little white cat.
A little white cat.
It's very...
She's quite dysfunctional.
What do you mean dysfunctional?
Well, I got her...
I got her from a market and she was way too young to be given away, but the mother
was already long gone, you know.
So I got this teeny little kitten and she was kind of like a stray, you know.
And so she's a little weird.
I think it's because she was, you know, separated from her mother from...
Psychological issues?
Yeah, maybe.
Poor kitten.
But it's okay, you know.
Just enough in a little spoonful of sugar can't fix it.
Right.
Is that a good idea to give your cat?
I don't know.
But that's what Jason does, apparently.
I wonder if his cat's got problems.
That's what I'm doing this weekend.
You want to come over?
You're going to have some sugar and just going to see what happens.
You feed the horses sugar, right?
Sugar cubes.
Oh, that's right.
I've seen people do that.
Yeah.
So, yeah, we're going to talk about pets, domestic pets such as hamsters, parrots, ferrets.
As opposed to like wild pets.
Well, yeah, you know, some people have tigers.
Right.
The guy in New York that had the alligator or something in his bathroom.
Mike Tyson has a tiger.
Somehow that doesn't surprise me.
Yeah, a lot of drug lords have cougars and panthers.
That's a different story.
Anyway.
So, on Friday, we are having part three.
And on Friday, we are having part three of our interview series where we are going through
the process of a job interview.
Yeah.
I think that's extremely useful, especially when we talk about people learning English,
you know.
Yeah.
English is used in the workplace in a lot of places.
Especially if you're applying for a job that requires you to speak some level of English.
They will do the interview sometimes in English or part of it in English.
So which part of the interview process is this week's lesson?
Part three is educational background.
Okay.
Yeah.
So you're talking about curriculum.
Curriculum vidae.
Yeah.
Busting out other languages here.
Well, yeah.
You're going to talk about...
Properly pronounced Latin there.
That was great.
Talk about things like what you majored in, if you have a minor, etc.
All that good stuff.
There's also an interesting point, I think, in that lesson about British universities.
All right.
So, those are the lessons that we have coming up this week for everyone.
And of course, we really want to know if you have any suggestions or maybe some specific
lesson topics that you would like for us to cover.
We have over like 230 lessons in our lesson library so far, but obviously there's always
room for more.
And if you guys have a specific topic you guys want to talk about.
Some interesting things that are coming up in May and June for everyone.
Yeah.
What's coming up in May and June?
We have things like going to the train station.
We're even going to have some topics about like sexual topics.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
Like the miracle of life or contraceptives.
There's some interesting lessons coming up in English Pod.
All right.
So, all part of learning.
I got to say, I'm pretty excited.
I know you are.
You're in a couple of these dialogues as well.
Jason's like, I speak English, but I'm going to sign up for English Pod anyways.
All right.
I can't wait.
So, that's all the time we have for today.
We'll see you guys at our website, EnglishPod.com.
And until next time.
Bye.
See you guys later.
EnglishPod.com.